Lace up and dream.
Sneakerella is a music, comedy, family film
directed by Elizabeth Allen Rosenbaum.
When El, an aspiring sneaker designer from Queens, meets Kira King, the fiercely independent daughter of legendary
basketball star and sneaker tycoon Darius King, sparks fly as the two bond over their mutual affinity for sneakers.
With a little nudge from his best friend and a sprinkle of Fairy Godfather magic, El finds the courage to
use his talent to pursue his dream of becoming a ‘legit’ sneaker designer in the industry.
El, played by Chosen Jacobs.
Kira King, played by Lexi Underwood.
Zelly, played by Kolton Stewart.
Sami, played by Devyn Nekoda.
Liv, played by Robyn Alomar.
Darius King, played by John Salley.
Sneakerella is a 2022 American musical comedy film directed by Elizabeth Allen Rosenbaum and
written by David Light & Joseph Raso, Tamara Chestna, Mindy Stern, and George Gore II.
A re-imagining of the classic fairy tale Cinderella, the film stars Chosen Jacobs, Lexi Underwood, Devyn Nekoda, Bryan
Terrell Clark, Kolton Stewart, Hayward Leach, Robyn Alomar, Yvonne Senat Jones, Juan Chioran, and John Salley.
Produced by Disney Channel and Jane Startz Productions, the
film was released on Disney+ on May 13, 2022.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
Sneakerella was nominated for 11 Children's and Family Emmy Awards at its inaugural ceremony, winning four awards
including Outstanding Fiction Special and Outstanding Music Direction and Composition for a Live Action Program.
The tone is lighthearted.